Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience delivering high-quality Ruby on Rails and iOS applications at scale. My focus is on time-to-market while ensuring maintainable solutions that meet real business needs. Currently seeking short-term or contract roles.

### Experience

Self Employed, Dublin Ireland, July 2022 - Present Launched several Web and Mobile app products from concept to deployment. See <a href="divo.blog/apps">divo.blog/apps</a>. [Ruby, Rails, Javascript, Node, iOS, Swift, AWS, Pulumi, Ansible, Nginx, Docker]

Staff Software Engineer, Zendesk San Francisco, Jan 2021 - June 2022 Moved to the Support Views team in October 2019, became Tech Lead in August 2021. Responsible for rearchitecture of a core product, delivering an ETL pipeline handling millions of events per day and improving query runtime from minutes to sub-second. [Apache Kafka, Ruby, Rails, Elasticsearch]

Senior Engineer, Zendesk Dublin, Jan 2018 - Jan 2021 Transitioned to back end team in September 2018 after delivery of large iOS project. Responsible for updating and maintaining large legacy Ruby on Rails code base. Delivered new microservice splitting functionality off from the monolith, enabling faster iteration and deployment. Previous to that took over the lead of iOS development for the Zendesk Support Mobile SDK. [SQL, Ruby, Rails, Javascript, iOS Development, Swift]

**Developer, Zendesk Dublin, Jan 2016 - Dec 2017** Led development for Zendesk Support and Chat iOS SDKs. Delivered a new iteration of the Support SDK using in-house Redux implementation for iOS. [Objective-C, Swift, Bash, Redux, XCTest]

Associate Developer, Zendesk Dublin, Oct 2014 - Dec 2015 Worked as part of a team adding features to the newly released Zendesk Mobile SDKs. [Objective-C]

MasterCard Ireland, 2012 Summer internship for 7 months. [Java, Oracle DBMS]

**IBM Ireland, 2011** Extreme Blue Summer internship for 3 months at IBM Ireland. [Javascript, MySQL]

#### Core Technical Skills

- Ruby on Rails (6+ years)
- iOS Development, Objective-C, Swift (4+ years)
- ETL Pipelines, Kafka, Elasticsearch
- AWS, Pulumi, Ansible, Docker
- JavaScript, Node.js, SQL

## Skills and Interests

Github Blog

### Education

Trinity College, Dublin, BA(mod), MCs., 2008 - 2013 Graduated Computer Science B.A.mod with First Class Honors, Grade I.I

# Referees

Available on request.